

Patrick Dwyer

Data Scientist at Manifold Group with 2+ years of experience (including internships). Experience in Software Development, Machine Learning, and DevOps. Interested in building software that improves the world at least a little bit. Based in Saint Louis but open to hybrid positions.

Experience

Manifold Group: Data Scientist

- Built CI pipeline for building and publishing back end machine learning and database management services as Docker containers to AWS ECR with GitLab
- Building database management and machine learning backend services in Python as Dockerized applications

Websanity: Web Developer

• Freelance Web Developer for Rulepop, an emerging rules reference platform for tabletop games

October 2023 - Present

- Defined postgres database schema in relation to machine learning model requirements and existing data pipeline constraints
- Developing real-time (<30 second response latency) online (learns in production) anomoly detection models on structured data

September 2023 - Present

July 2023 - Sep 2023

 Implemented search using Fuse.js, page sharing using share api and dynamic title switching for all live rules references

Schwartz Lab: Lab Tech

- Developed supervised 3d Convolutional Neural Network in
 PyTorch
- Set up extrinsic camera calibration routine by implementing Levenberg-Marquardt for Bundle Adjustment
- Extended PyTorch torch.autograd.Function class to integrate 3d→2d point projection into autograd
- Manually labelled 8,544 ground truth 2d points using selfmade image labeling program

Technical Skills

Languages

Python, SQL, Javascript, CSS, SCSS, HTML, Bash(Unix shell)

Tools

Docker, ECR, Postgres (RDS), Node.js, npm, git, GitHub Actions, GitLab CI/CD, Tower, Visual Studio Code, Jupyter

Libraries

node:http, node:fs, Fuse.js, NumPy, PyTorch, Matplotlib, Pandas, PySpark, OpenCV, Flask

Education

BA: Mathematics, Computer Science

Sep 2019 - June 2023

Northwestern University, Evanston, IL — Weinberg College of Arts and Sciences — 3.43/4.00 GPA

Projects

patrickdwyer.com

Summer 2023-Present

• Responsive CV website built from scratch using no pre-built libraries and industry best practices

LLVM Compiler (Class: Compiler Construction)

Winter 2022

• Built an LLVM→Assembly compiler in C++